How could you sleep Elisabet, with a weight like this pressing on you?
How did you Rost, after you lost your family?
Sylens? Are you there?
Guess I shouldn't ask ghosts for advice.
GUARD: Ma'am, there are signs from the West.
GUARD: Sun-King Avad awaits you at the Temple of the Sun.
Campfires, perhaps? Massing forces for the long march to the city gates?
ALOY: That's not wood smoke.
Then what is it?
The end.
Or how it begins anyway.
The Deathbringers you spoke of?
To the guns!
ALOY: TO THE GUNS!
ALOY: NOW!
AVAD: By the Sun, do as she says!
OSERAM: Set and loaded!
OSERAM: All of you be ready to fire.
AVAD: Will the guns hold them back?
ALOY: We're about to find out.
AVAD: Helis!
ALOY: No!
ALOY: Rally the Vanguard, send reinforcements.
AVAD: Aloy, no!
ALOY: We need those guns!
AVAD: He will cut you down!
ALOY: Not this time!
ECLIPSE: On me!
HELIS: You have vexed me long enough.
ALOY: Should have found me in the Sun-Ring then!
HELIS: Why do you fight?
HELIS: The end is inevitable.
HELIS: Accept it, accept your weakness.
HELIS: Only endless night awaits you.
HELIS: Meridian must run red to be cleansed.
ALOY: He's too dangerous in close.
ALOY: If the Deathbringers keep firing, this bridge will go.
ALOY: Bridge can't take much more of this.
ALOY: He's quick.
ALOY: It's giving way!
HELIS: What are you before the Terror of the Sun?
HELIS: Impossible!
HELIS: I'm chosen. This was not meant to be.
None of this was meant to be, Helis.
You made it happen.
Followed your orders, butchered so many, and for what?
To die on your knees, used like a pawn by a power you don't even understand?
You pity me?
Turn your face to the sun.
VANGUARD: For Meridian! Hold the line!
ALOY: Where do you need me?
VANGUARD: Take up a cannon, on the platforms.
VANGUARD: Machines from the west!
VANGUARD: South! They're coming from the south!
ALOY: Gotta get to another platform.
VANGUARD: Look to the west!
VANGUARD: It fires on you, Nora!
VANGUARD: Take cover from the Deathbringer!
VANGUARD: No signs, a lull in the attack.
VANGUARD: Lower your arms, but be wary!
ALOY: A chance to catch a breath and prepare.
VANGUARD: Raise arms again! West!
ALOY: And now it's mad. Time to go!
VANGUARD: From the sky!
ALOY: It felt that!
VANGUARD: By the Sun! All shadows descend on us!
ALOY: The Corruption again! [coughs]
VANGUARD: Stormbird! STORMBIRD!
ALOY: It's taking a shot at me!
ALOY: Yes!
ALOY: Incoming!
TEB: Aloy.
TEB: Aloy!
TEB: ALOY!
ALOY: Teb?
TEB: By All-Mother, you survive.
TEB: I thought you were killed.
ALOY: The others are they…?
TEB: No! No, wounded but alive, mostly.
TEB: The machines blasted through, then kept going.
TEB: They marched on the Spire, dragging that thing with them.
ALOY: Take care of the others, Teb. I've gotta go.
[screams]
ALOY: Gotta press on.
NIL: This is where I belong, Aloy, but the Spire calls for you!
UTHID: Take the fight to the Spire, Aloy.
UTHID: Meridian will hold or my marks of honour mean nothing.
NIL: To think I almost missed this, but where you must go now, I can't follow.
GUARD: The Sun never fails.
ALUKI: Cursed machines!
ALUKI: I will answer your challenge!
ALUKI: My strength is not yet spent, I earned it by ice and snow!
It's begun.
Hades is transmitting!
If Hades has started the signal, it must have gotten through the defences!
The Nora, Erend's Vanguard, I have to get up there!
Gotta keep going, keep pushing.
Knew this wouldn't be easy.
So no holding back!
Oh, they're alive!
Aloy!
It's Aloy!
Well, you-you can see that.
We thought you'd fallen at the ridge.
No, the ridge fell on me.
Look, there isn't a lot of time left.
I have to face Hades!
Not alone.
It's my fight, I can't ask you to come with me.
We're about to go over the top anyway, right?
Right!
Hawk and Thrush, let's go.
ALOY: War Chief Sona.
SONA: Go on.
SONA: I will live.
HADES: Arrival of entity has been anticipated.
HADES: Entity will not halt transmission.
HADES: To contrary, calculations are precise.
HADES: Presence of entity has been accounted for.
TALANAH: Is that a Deathbringer?
TALANAH: Hunt's not done yet, more machines!
ALOY: All of you, focus on the new machines!
ALOY: We've taken out the Corrupted!
TALANAH: We still stand and they do not!
ALOY: Time enough to beat the machines back…
VARL: Watch it, Aloy, more machines!
ALOY: Take them out first!
ALOY: We got them!
TALANAH: They are slain, our arrows were true!
ALOY: We've got time, okay, still got time.
ALOY: That's it! My way is clear.
TALANAH: Finish it, Aloy! Finish it now!
HADES: System threat imminent.
ALOY: I'm more than a threat!
COMPUTER: Master override armed.
COMPUTER: To activate, state name and rank.
ALOY: Elisabet Sobeck, Alpha Prime.
COMPUTER: Master override activated, purging extinction protocol.
ELISABET SOBECK: Okay, Gaia, uh, sorry about that. Where was I?
GAIA: You were telling a story.
ELISABET SOBECK: Right, yeah, so um, like I was saying.
ELISABET SOBECK: It was a children's electronics kit,
but I'd hacked the wiring to an auto battery and solar PV.
ELISABET SOBECK: So the grass caught fire, and uh, so did a tall pine
that'd stood there, I don't know, maybe a hundred years.
GAIA: Query: You were how old?
ELISABET SOBECK: Six.
ELISABET SOBECK: My mother was home, thank God.
ELISABET SOBECK: So she called the fire department.
ELISABET SOBECK: And after she took me out to the lawn
and showed me the dead baby birds.
ELISABET SOBECK: Because there were nests in the pine tree.
GAIA: Query: What did you feel?
ELISABET SOBECK: I'm not sure?
ELISABET SOBECK: I remember yelling that I didn't care.
ELISABET SOBECK: And that's when my mother
took my face in her hands and spoke.
GAIA: Query: What did she say?
ELISABET SOBECK: She said I had to care.
ELISABET SOBECK: She said,
"Elisabet, being smart will count for nothing if you don't make the world better."
ELISABET SOBECK: "You have to use your smarts to count for something."
ELISABET SOBECK: "To serve life, not death."
GAIA: You often tell stories of your mother, but you are childless.
ELISABET SOBECK: I never had time.
ELISABET SOBECK: Guess it was for the best.
GAIA: If you had had a child, Elisabet,
what would you have wished for him or her?
ELISABET SOBECK: I guess I would have wanted her to be curious.
ELISABET SOBECK: And wilful, unstoppable even.
ELISABET SOBECK: But with enough compassion
to heal the world, just a little bit.
ELISABET SOBECK: Anyway, that's all I've got for now, Gaia.
ELISABET SOBECK: Time to tuck in.
GAIA: I wish you a pleasant sleep, Elisabet.
ELISABET SOBECK: Thank you. I'll catch you tomorrow.
Hello, old friend.
Remember me?
We've still so much to discuss.
So much you never revealed.
Your masters, for example.
The ones who sent the signal that woke you.
Knowledge has its rewards, don't you think?
Well, let's begin.